Guide to the Otis Olney Wright Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
Otis Olney Wright Papers
1868-1918
RG 69
Yale University Divinity School Library
4
(11 boxes)
Sermons, scrapbooks, notes, and writings document the work of an Episcopal clergyman in New England during the last part of the 19th century and the first two decades of the 20th century. Otis Olney Wright was an Episcopal clergyman. He served St. John's Church in Sandy Hook, CT from 1891 to ca. 1917.
Wright, Otis Olney
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Otis Olney Wright was ordained as a deacon and priest in the Episcopal Church ca. 1881-1882. He was the rector of St. John' Church, Sandy Hook, Connecticut from 1891 to ca. 1917.
Scope and Contents
Notes, writings, sermons, and scrapbooks provide documentation of the work and context of an Episcopal clergyman in New England at the turn of the century. The scrapbooks contain clippings of writings by Wright and area town news. The majority of the sermons in this collection were preached in St. John's Church, Sandy Hook.
Arrangement
I. Notes and Writings, 1873-1915
II. Scrapbooks, 1877-1912
III. Sermons, 1868-1917
IV. Collected Material, 1878-1918
Clergy; Wright, Otis Olney; Episcopal Church -- Connecticut
- Notes and Writings, 1873-1915; Series I
  - Lecture notes, 1873 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - "Original Poems" by OOW, 1880-1915 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Two volumes of miscellaneous notes, 1875, n.d. (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Misc. writings by OOW (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Mics. writings by OOW (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Scrapbooks, 1877-1912; Series II
  - "Contributions published in The People's Home Journal, Dayton, Ohio; The Young Churchman, Milwaukee, WI; The Orphanage Record, Providence, RI; Trinity Church Paper, Newport, RI; and editorials in the Swansea Record, Fall River, MA", 1877-1887 (Box 1)
  - "Contributions published in the Newtown Bee, Newtown, CT", 1891-1899 (Box 1)
  - "Published in the Newtown Bee", 1903-1904 (Box 1)
  - " Bee " and other writings, 1900-1905 (Box 1)
  - " Bee ", 1905-1908 (Box 1)
  - " Bee ", 1910-1912 (Box 1)
- Sermons, 1868-1917; Series III
  - Sermons, 1868-1883 (Box 2, Folder 2-5)
  - Sermons, 1884-1893 (Box 3, Folder 6-10)
  - Sermons, 1894-1896 (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - Sermons, 1897-1899 (Box 5, Folder 14-16)
  - Sermons, 1900-1902 (Box 6, Folder 17-19)
  - Sermons, 1903-1906 (Box 7, Folder 20-23)
  - Sermons, 1907-1910 (Box 8, Folder 24-27)
  - Sermons, 1911-1917 (Box 9, Folder 28-29)
  - fragments and undated (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Collected Material, 1878-1918; Series IV
  - 3 letters addressed to OOW, 1878, 1891, 1918 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Writings by others (Box 10, Folder 33)
  - Certificate from Connecticut Historical Society (Box 10, Folder 33)